<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[keketter]]></title>
  <link href="http://keketter.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://keketter.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-08T16:38:16+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://keketter.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[keke_ta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[keketter@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quotes from Sam Altman]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/08/quotes-from-sam-altman/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T12:30:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/08/quotes-from-sam-altman</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LooptのFounder、Sam Altmanの名言を引用メモ。(約5年前）</p>

<blockquote><p>-Get ready for high highs and low lows, and practice keeping yourself in the middle or you&#8217;ll never get good work done. You&#8217;re going to be pretty sure your company is dying at least once a month, and it usually isn&#8217;t. This is very important and very difficult to learn.</p>

<p>-Focus on the product, especially in the early days. You&#8217;ll have time to make deals later. Now, you&#8217;ve got to build something great.</p>

<p>-If you hire, do it very slowly and carefully. The culture of a company is set very early, and so is the quality of the team.</p>

<p>-Don&#8217;t be afraid to change your idea if the market seems bad. Early is a good time to do it. You can change your product, you can change your team, you can change your sales strategy, but you can probably not create a market. Good startups surf someone else&#8217;s wave.</p>

<p>-Figure out what the important things are, and spend lots time on those and little on the rest. Lots of startups work very hard, but on the wrong things. They still die an untimely death.</p>

<p>-Watch out for fights and brewing tension among cofounders (ie, make sure everyone feels they have a reasonably fair deal). I&#8217;ve seen this derail more early startups than anything else. And, if you are really sure you have the wrong cofounder, fire fast.</p>

<p>-The startups in my Y Combinator &#8216;class&#8217; that tanked the fastest were the ones that spent the most time worrying about option grants for members of their board of advisors and the least time on their product. Could be a coincidence, but why risk it? Build your product.</p>

<p>-Great products, technology, and people win the day in the long run. History backs this up. Do not be afraid of competitors without them, no matter how much money they raise or how much noise they make.</p>

<p>-It&#8217;s most tempting to give up right before you&#8217;re about to succeed.</p>

<p>Best of luck, Sam Altman <br/>
-（<a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=95857">More advice for new Y Combinator founders</a>より）</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_Distortion_Field">現実歪曲フィールド</a>とは
Steve Jobsがもっている現実を歪ませるほどのカリスマ的影響力のことを指して言われるが、GreplinのDaniel Gross曰く、Sam Altmanにも同様の現実歪曲フィールドがあるという。(GrossはPaul Grahamにもあると言っている）<small>※<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Startups-Open-Sourced-ebook/dp/B004ZULMR6">「Startups Open Sourced」</a>より</small></p>

<p>またSam Altmanは、Paul Grahamにここ30年で最も惹かれるFounder五人のうちの一人だと称されている。</p>

<blockquote><p>According to Paul Graham, Loopt&#8217;s Sam Altman is one of the five most interesting founders of the last three decades. There&#8217;s a simple reason for it: he really knows what he&#8217;s doing.</p></blockquote>

<p>StripeのFounder、Patrick Collisonも、Stripeのアーリー期にSam Altmanのアドバイスにどれほど助けられたかについて<a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3559624">コメント</a>している。(SamはStripeに初期から投資している）</p>

<blockquote><p>His advice has consistently been clear, useful, and correct. He&#8217;s also gone way beyond the call of duty in helping us on a number of occasions.</p>

<p>Though this is only tangentially related to the story, I&#8217;ll take the chance to say: if you ever happen to have the chance to have Sam invest in your company, I strongly recommend availing of it.</p></blockquote>

<p>Sam Altmanのその他の素晴らしい名言は<a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/threads?id=sama">Hacker News上のコメント</a>で。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square and Dwolla (Transactions Per Day)]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/08/square-and-dwolla-transactions-per-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T09:14:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/08/square-and-dwolla-transactions-per-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Square: $11M~</strong> (2011年末)      <br/>
<strong>Dwolla: $1M~</strong>  (2012年2月)</p>

<p>Dwollaのペースすごー。<a href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/02/07/dwolla-gettin-freaky/">$5M調達</a>おめ。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/07/progress-report/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T13:39:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/07/progress-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Setting aside time on a daily or weekly basis to reflect on the day is a powerful productivity hack.</p></blockquote>

<p>先週何をやったか。なんてことはない一週間の進捗報告だけど、
きっちりできるかどうかで組織の生産性は大きく違ってくる。  <br/>
シリコンバレーの有名企業は、かっこいいプロジェクトネームまでつけてこの進捗報告を習慣化している。
記事によると、Googleでは「Snippets」という週間進捗をメールする習慣、Facebookでは「Colbert」という同様の習慣がある。
Squareでは名前はないけど、社員がCOOのKeith Raboisに週間進捗を直接メールしている。
<small>(Raboisの仕事量<sup>^<sup>^;)</small></sup></sup></p>

<p>さりげなく強調されているのは、進捗は<strong>「メール」</strong>で報告すること。</p>

<blockquote><p>At Palantir, they do email snippets because they have a very strong culture against meetings.  In addition, email as an interface avoids the issues with, for instance, CRMs, where employees spend valuable time logging into a system and entering highly structured information or they don’t use it at all.</p></blockquote>

<p>生産性の秘密は、当たり前のことを怠らないことにある。自戒をこめて＞＜</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solve for X]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/07/solve-for-x/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T10:11:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/07/solve-for-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Googleの興味深いプロジェクトがリークされている。
詳しくは今後発表されるだろうけど、
世の中のあらゆる問題に対してクレイジーな解決策を議論する場らしい。
GeekっぽいTEDみたいな感じになるんだろうか。</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/uDDy7QSdt6A?feature=player_embedded" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zen]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/06/zen/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T19:55:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/06/zen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>去年の夏ごろに書かれたPaul Buchheitのエッセイ、<a href="http://paulbuchheit.blogspot.com/2011/08/i-am-nothing.html">I am nothing</a>
が禅の考え方にとても近い。</p>

<blockquote><p>By returning to zero expectations, by accepting that I am nothing, it is easier to see the truth. Fear, jealousy, insecurity, unfairness, embarrassment &#8211; these feelings cloud our ability to see what is.</p></blockquote>

<p>Ben Horowitzもこれに近いことを起業家の教訓として
<a href="http://bhorowitz.com/2011/10/08/nobody-cares/">Nobody Cares</a>という題で書いている。</p>

<blockquote><p>That might be the best CEO advice ever. Because, you see, nobody cares. When things go wrong in your company, nobody cares. The press doesn’t care, your investors don’t care, your board doesn’t care, your employees don’t care, even your mama doesn’t care. Nobody cares.</p></blockquote>

<p>個人的に好きな2つのエッセイ。
ネガティブなとき、読み返したい。</p>

<p>禅といえば<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D1R-jKKp3NA">このひと</a>も。</p>

<blockquote><p>Almost everything&#8211;all external expectations, all pride, all fear of embarrassment or failure&#8211;these things just fall away in the face of death, leaving only what is truly important. Remembering that you are going to die is the best way I know to avoid the trap of thinking you have something to lose. You are already naked. There is no reason not to follow your heart.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intern at Mixpanel]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/05/mixpanel-intern/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T21:06:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/05/mixpanel-intern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mixpanelのインターン生がQA形式でMixpanelでのインターン経験を語っている。</p>

<p>FounderのSuhail Doshiは、学生時代にMax LevchinのいたSlideでインターンをしたのがきっかけで、
Startupの世界にのめり込んでいったというから、人一倍思い入れが強いらしい。
Suhail Doshiは、SlideのインターンなくしてMixpanelはなかった、とも言っている。
そのMax LevchinはMixpanelに出資している。
<a href="http://mixpanel.com/about/">Mixpanelの投資家陣</a>はさりげなく豪華だったと思い出す。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Successful Startups in Show HN.]]></title>
    <link href="http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/05/successful-startups-in-show-hn/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T20:59:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://keketter.com/blog/2012/02/05/successful-startups-in-show-hn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Show HNに投稿されてきたなかで成功したStartupをあげようぜ、というスレ。(Hacker News)</p>

<p>Drew Houstonの<a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863">投稿(Dropbox)</a>やCharlie Cheeverの<a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1197146">投稿(Quora)</a>が上がっている。それぞれ5年前と3年前の投稿である。なかなか味のあるスレ。</p>

<p>pgさんはDropboxをあげてる。</p>

<blockquote><p>pg 6 days ago | link   <br/>
http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
